Guide to the New York University Archives Collection of Course Bulletins MC.286
New York University Archives
- College of Arts and Science (Washington Square) (RG 19), 1903-2016, 2014-ongoing
  - College of Arts and Science Academic Programs, August 2018-March 2021 (Box Electronic Records)
    Homepage for information about academic programs in the College of Arts and Science. Contains links to majors and minors programs of study, cross-school and pre-professional programs, the college core curriculum, the CAS bulletin, the accelerated bachelor's-master's, women in science, and first-year seminar program.
  - College of Arts and Science Majors and Minors, October 2018-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)
    Listing of all majors and minors offered at the College of Arts and Science.
  - College of Arts and Science Bulletin Departments and Programs, February 2019-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)
    Website listing the college core curriculum, seminars, and major and minors in the College of Arts and Science. Each program and/or department page contains a program of study (major and/or minor requirements) and course offerings page.
  - College of Arts and Science College Core Curriculum, December 2019-June 2021 (Box Electronic Records)
    Information on the core curriculum for the College of Arts and Science The website is made up of course descriptions for the core classes (Quantitative Reasoning, Physical Science, Life Science, Natural Science, Conversations of the West, Text and Ideas, World Cultures, Cultures and Contexts, Societies and the Social Sciences, Expressive Culture, and Global Academic Centers) dating back to 2001.
  - College of Arts and Science Bulletin, April 2020-June 2022 (Box Electronic Records)
    PDF and online versions of the College of Arts and Science Bulletin beginning in 2018. The website is broken down by departments and programs and each departmental page contains a program of study and course offerings with descriptions.
  - College of Arts and Science Bulletin 2020-2022, November 2020-February 2022 (Box Electronic Records)
    PDF of the College of Arts and Science Bulletin for 2020-2022.
  - College of Arts and Science Core Curriculum, April 2021-February 2022 (Box Electronic Records)
    The page contains course descriptions for the College of Arts and Science core curriculum subject areas: Quantitative Reasinging, Physical Science, Life Science, Texts and Ideas, Cultures and Contexts, Societies and the Social Sciences, Expressive Culture, and Global Academic Centers. The course descriptions date back to 2014-2015.
  - College of Arts and Science First-Year Seminars, October 2021-February 2022 (Box Electronic Records)
    Course descriptions for first year seminars in the College of Arts and Science.
  - College of Arts and Science Core Curriculum, March 2022-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)
    The page contains course descriptions for the College of Arts and Science core curriculum subject areas: Quantitative Reasoning, Physical Science, Life Science, Texts and Ideas, Cultures and Contexts, Societies and the Social Sciences, Expressive Culture, and Global Academic Centers. The course descriptions are for the 2022-2023 academic year.
  - College of Arts and Science College Core Curriculum Summer 2022 Courses, March-June 2022 (Box Electronic Records)
    The page contains course descriptions for the College of Arts and Science core curriculum for Summer 2022.
  - College of Arts and Science First-Year Seminars, October 2022-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)
    Course descriptions for first year seminars in the College of Arts and Science for the 2022-2023 academic year.
- Evening College of Arts and Science (RG 19.3), 1965-1968
  - Bulletins, 1965-1968 (Box 172)
- Graduate School of Arts and Sciences (RG 20), 1885-2017, 2014-ongoing
  - Graduate School Circulars and Catalogues, 1885-1901 (Box 210, Folder 3)
  - Special Announcement, Supplementary to page 92 of the University Catalogue, The University of the City of New York, 1886-1987 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - New York University Graduate School Announcements for the Fifteenth Year, 1900-1901 (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - New York University Graduate School, Department of Philosophy General Statement, 1901-1902 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - New York University Graduate School Announcements (Incomplete), 1904-1905 (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - New York University Graduate School, Latin Courses, 1906-1907 (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Requirements for the Doctorate and Publicity and the Doctorate, 1911 (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - New York University Bulletin, Graduate School Department of Classics, "The Excavations at Tell Ajjul" with Announcements of the Department for the Session, 1932-1933 (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - New York University Bulletin, Washington Square College Graduate School, Department of Government, Division of Research in Public Administration, Announcements for the Session, 1934-1935 (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - New York University Bulletin, Graduate School, Announcements for the Session, 1936-1937 (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - New York University Bulletin, Graduate School, Announcements for the Session, 1937-1938 (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - New York University Bulletin, Graduate School, Announcements for the Session, 1938-1939 (Box 34, Folder 11)
  - New York University Bulletin, Graduate School, Announcements for the Session, 1939-1940 (Box 34, Folder 12)
  - New York University Bulletin, Graduate School of Arts and Science, Announcements for the Session, 1940-1941 (Box 34, Folder 13)
  - Bulletins, 1901-1912 (Box 211)
  - Bulletins, 1913-1918 (Box 214)
  - Bulletins, 1921-1930 (Box 214)
  - Bulletins, 1930-1937 (Box 214)
  - Bulletins, 1937-1942 (Box 214)
  - Graduate School of Arts and Science Bulletins, 1942-1948 (Box 215, Folder 4)
  - Bulletins, 1947-1967 (Box 35)
  - Bulletins, 1948-1953 (Volume RG20 Bulletins - Bound 1948-1953)
  - Bulletins, 1953-1957 (Volume RG20 Bulletins - Bound 1953-1957)
  - Bulletins, 1957-1962 (Volume RG20 Bulletins - Bound 1957-1962)
  - Bulletins, 1962-1967 (Volume RG20 Bound 1962-1967)
  - Bulletins, 1967-1974 (Box 36)
  - Bulletins, 1974-1976 (Box 37)
  - Bulletins, 1976-1982 (Box 38)
  - Bulletins, 1982-1990 (Box 39)
  - Bulletins, 1990-1996 (Box 40)
  - Bulletins, 1996-2001 (Box 41)
  - Bulletins, 2001-2005, 2009-2011 (Box 42)
    Includes Applications for Admission and Financial Aid (2003-2005).
  - Bulletins (PDFs), 2001-2017 (Box Electronic Records)
  - Graduate School of Arts and Science Bulletin, April 2014-February 2019 (Box Electronic Records)
    The Graduate School offers the degrees of M.A., M.S., M.F.A., and Ph.D. in most areas of the humanities, social sciences, and natural sciences. Several advanced certificate programs are offered.
  - Graduate School of Arts and Science Bulletin 2017-2019, November 2017-October 2019 (Box Electronic Records)
    NYU Course Bulletin PDF for Graduate School of Arts and Sciences, which includes the academic calendar, brief descriptions of departments and degree programs, and course listings by degree program.
  - Graduate School of Arts and Science Bulletin, November 2017-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)
    Landing page for the GSAS bulletin. Contains PDFs of bulletins starting in 2001.
  - Graduate School of Arts and Science Bulletin, October 2021-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)
    PDF of the Graduate School of Arts and Science Bulletin for 2021-2023.
  - Graduate School of Arts and Science Bulletin, November 2022-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)
- Institute of Fine Arts (RG 20.1), 1923-2016, 2014-ongoing
  - Bulletins, 1923-1924, 1926-1929, 1935-1942, 1944-1945, 1954-1968 (Box 43)
    Includes Department of Fine Arts.
  - Bulletins, 1968-1978 (Box 44)
  - Bulletins, 1979-1991 (Box 45)
  - Bulletins, 1991-2001 (Box 46)
  - Bulletins, 2007-2009, 2010-2011 (Box 47)
  - Previously Taught Courses in the History of Art and Archaeology 2005-2015 (PDF) (Box Electronic Records)
  - History of Art and Archaeology Courses (PDFs), 2015-2016 (Box Electronic Records)
  - Previously Taught Courses in Conservation 2005-2015 (PDF) (Box Electronic Records)
  - Conservation Courses (PDFs), 2015-2016 (Box Electronic Records)
  - Institute of Fine Arts Course Descriptions, April 2014-June 2020 (Box Electronic Records)
    The landing page for the Institute of Fine Arts academics. It contains degree requirements for the PhD, Masters Degree, and Conservation concentration as well as course descriptions in Art History and Conservation starting in Fall 2014.
  - Institute of Fine Arts Master of Arts, May 2014-October 2019 (Box Electronic Records)
    Institute of Fine Arts Master of Arts degree requirements, course definitions, and sample full-time and part-time MA degree schedules. The page also features links to other resources provided by the Institute.
  - Institute of Fine Arts Doctorate of Philosophy Degree Requirements, May 2014-October 2019 (Box Electronic Records)
    NYU's Institute of Fine Arts webpage detailing the requirements for a Doctorate of Philosophy, including distribution requirements for course load, language requirements, funding information, and other degree requirements. The page also features links to other information like events calendars from the Institute.
  - Institute of Fine Arts Conservation Fall Course Offerings, July 2014-October 2020 (Box Electronic Records)
    PDFs of the fall course offerings and descriptions for conservation at the Institute of Fine Arts from 2014-2020. 2015 is missing.
  - Institute of Fine Arts Art History Fall Course Offerings, July 2014-October 2020 (Box Electronic Records)
    PDFs of the fall course offerings and descriptions for Art History at the Institute of Fine Arts from 2014-2020. 2015 is missing.
  - Institute of Fine Arts Conservation Spring Course Offerings, July 2014-October 2019 (Box Electronic Records)
    PDF listing the Conservation course offerings for the Spring semester.
  - Institute of Fine Arts Art History Spring Course Offerings, July 2014-October 2019 (Box Electronic Records)
    PDF listing the Art History course offerings for the Spring semester.
  - Institute of Fine Arts Conservation Center Program Overview, September 2016-October 2019 (Box Electronic Records)
    This website details the Conservation graduate program, and includes details about the core curriculum and sample schedules of courses, as well as links to latest internship placements, course descriptions from past semesters, and other pages on the Institute site.
  - Institute of Fine Arts Fall 2020 Curricular Plan, October 2020 (Box Electronic Records)
    Plan for in-person coursework at the IFA during the COVID-19 pandemic.
  - Institute of Fine Arts Conservation Spring Course Offerings, March 2021 (Box Electronic Records)
  - Institute of Fine Arts Art History Spring Course Offerings, March 2021 (Box Electronic Records)
  - Institute of Fine Arts Academics, March 2021-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)
    Website describing the degree requirements for the PhD, Masters program, and Conservation program at the IFA. Aso includes links to PDF course descriptions by semester and the IFA Handbook.
  - Institute of Fine Arts Art History Fall Course Offerings, March 2021-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)
    PDF listing the Art History course offerings for the Fall semester.
  - Institute of Fine Arts Conservation Fall Course Offerings, March 2021-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)
    PDF listing the Conservation course offerings for the Fall semester.
  - Institute of Fine Arts Core Conservation Courses, April 2021-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)
    PDF of the core conservation course offerings at the Institute of Fine Arts.
  - Institute of Fine Arts Handbook, April 2021-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)
    PDF of the Student Handbook for the Institute of Fine Arts. Contains degree requirements for the MA, PHD, and Conservation programs.
- Courant Institute of Mathematical Sciences (RG 20.2), 1965-1987, 2014-ongoing
  - Bulletins, 1965-1975, 1980-1983 (Box 48)
    Includes Graduate Program in Computer Science bulletin (1982).
  - Bulletins, 1985-1987 (Box 49)
  - Courant Institute Educational Programs, May 2014-May 2016 (Box Electronic Records)
    Courant Institute of Mathematical Sciences is a center for research and advanced training in mathematics and computer science. The Institute has long been a leader in mathematical analysis, applied mathematics, and scientific computation, with special emphasis on partial differential equations and their applications. In computer science, the Institute excels in theory, programming languages, computer graphics, and parallel computing. Mathematics and computer science are viewed as living parts of the stream of science, not as isolated specialties. They offer Master of Science (M.S.) and Ph.D. programs in both mathematics and computer science. Courant is affiliated with the Graduate School of Arts and Science.
  - Master of Science Program Mathematics in Finance, July 2014-September 2016 (Box Electronic Records)
    Homepage for the Mathematics in Finance Masters program at the Courant Institute of Mathematical Sciences.
  - Master of Science in Mathematics Program, July 2014-September 2016 (Box Electronic Records)
    Webpage describing the program for the Master of Science in Mathematics, including degree requirements, course listings, examinations, thesis, and academic standards.
  - Department of Mathematics The Master of Science in Scientific Computing, July 2014-September 2016 (Box Electronic Records)
    Program information for the Master of Science in Scientific Computing at Courant Institute of Mathematical Sciences, including admission and degree requirements, computational master's thesis, and capstone project.
  - Department of Mathematics PhD Programs, July 2014-September 2016 (Box Electronic Records)
    The page contains information on degree requirements for the PhD in Mathematics, PhD in Atmosphere Ocean Science and Mathematics, and the PhD in Computational Biology.
  - Department of Mathematics, Courant Institute, July 2014-October 2016 (Box Electronic Records)
    Website for the NYU Math undergraduate program.
  - Courant Institute of Mathematical Sciences Homepage, May-September 2016 (Box Electronic Records)
    Homepage for Courant Institute of Mathematical Sciences. Includes information on the Institute; academic programs; research areas and centers, faculty recognition; staff, students, and faculty; news and events; press releases, alumni news, newsletters, and offered seminars.
  - Program in Computational Biology, September 2016 (Box Electronic Records)
    Website for the computational biology program. Areas of research include Macromolecular Modeling, Computational Genomics, Physiological Modeling, and Cellular and Biological Imaging.
  - Graduate Program Center for Atmosphere Ocean Science, September 2016 (Box Electronic Records)
    Website containing information for the graduate program for the Center for Atmosphere Ocean Science. Includes information on how to apply to the PhD program, the program philosophy, degree requirements, financial aid, and the program flyer.
  - Courant Institute of Mathematical Sciences Master's of Science in Information Systems (MSIS), September 2016-November 2017 (Box Electronic Records)
    Degree requirements and sample courses for the Master's of Science in Information Systems.
  - Courant Institute of Mathematical Sciences Master in Computer Science, September 2016-November 2017 (Box Electronic Records)
    Webpage for the Masters in Computer Science at Courant Institute of Mathematical Sciences. Contains degree requirements and sample courses.
  - NYU Center for Urban Science and Progress MS Program Curriculum, September 2016-November 2017 (Box Electronic Records)
    Website containing the program length, core curriculum, and program tracks for the Applied Urban Science and Informatics program.
  - Courant Institute of Mathematical Sciences Computer Science PhD Program Overview, September 2016-October 2020 (Box Electronic Records)
    Website that contains an overview of the PhD program including information on admission, degree requirements, resources, and achievements.
  - Courant Institute of Mathematical Sciences Course Catalog, September 2016-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)
    Course descriptions offered at NYU Courant in computer science. Organized by graduate and undergraduate levels.
  - NYU Computer Science Requirements for Masters in Information Systems, September 2016-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)
    Listings of the required Computer Science, Stern, and/or Information Technology Projects courses for the Masters in Information Systems.
  - NYU Computer Science Undergraduate Education, September 2016-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)
    Overview of the undergraduate Computer Science program at Courant Institute of Mathematical Sciences. Includes information on the major and minor programs courses.
  - Courant Institute of Mathematical Sciences PhD Degree Requirements, September 2016-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)
    The website goes over the degree requirements for a PhD in computer science, including breadth requirements, depth requirements, thesis defense, and courses that can meet the requirements.
  - Courant Institute of Mathematical Sciences Mathematics Undergraduate Course Descriptions, April 2017-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)
    This page features undergraduate course offerings for New York University's Courant School of Mathematics, including descriptions, term offerings, corequisites, and prerequisites. Later versions of this webpage sorts by what classes are offered at NYU Tandon or the College of Arts and Science.
  - Courant Institute of Mathematical Sciences Mathematics Graduate Course Descriptions, April 2017-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)
    This page features graduate course offerings for New York University's Courant School of Mathematics, including descriptions, prerequisites, and required and recommended texts. There is also information about time and instructor for each course. Because this page is hosted on the Courant Institute of Mathematical Sciences site, there are links to other resources for students in this or other mathematics degree programs offered at Courant.
- Institute for the Study of the Ancient World (RG 21.38), April 2014-ongoing
  - Institute for the Study of the Ancient World - Current Seminar Descriptions, April-May 2014 (Box Electronic Records)
    The Institute for the Study of the Ancient World is a center for advanced scholarly research and graduate education, intended to cultivate comparative and connective investigations of the ancient world. It will feature doctoral and postdoctoral programs, with the aim of training a new generation of scholars who will enter the global academic community and become intellectual leaders.
  - Institute for the Study of the Ancient World Course Descriptions, September 2016-March 2021 (Box Electronic Records)
    Course descriptions for ISAW seminars dating back to Fall 2016.
  - Institute for the Study of the Ancient World Past Seminars, September 2016-ongoing (Box Electronic Records)
    Past seminars offered at the Institute for the Study of the Ancient World, dating back to Fall 2009. Contains seminar titles, course descriptions, times the course was offered, and the professor teaching the course.
- Liberal Studies Program (Graduate School) (RG 20.8), 1989-1990
  - Bulletins, 1989-1990 (Box 50)
- NYU/Manhattanville College (RG 20.10), 1978-1982
  - Bulletins, 1978-1982 (Box 50)
- New York College of Music (RG 21.8), 1899-1930
  - Catalogue of the New York College of Music, 1899-1900 (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - Catalogue of the New York College of Music, 1904-1905 (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - Catalogue of the New York College of Music, 1906-1907 (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - Catalogue of the New York College of Music, 1909-1910 (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - Catalogue of the New York College of Music, 1910-1911 (Box 51, Folder 5)
  - Catalogue of the New York College of Music, 1913-1914 (Box 51, Folder 6)
  - Catalogue of the New York College of Music, 1914-1915 (Box 51, Folder 7)
  - Catalogue of the New York College of Music, 1915-1916 (Box 51, Folder 8)
  - Catalogue of the New York College of Music, 1920-1921 (Box 51, Folder 9)
  - Catalogue of the New York College of Music, 1921-1922 (Box 51, Folder 10)
  - Catalogue of the New York College of Music, 1922-1923 (Box 51, Folder 11)
  - Catalogue of the New York College of Music, 1924-1925 (Box 51, Folder 12)
  - Catalogue of the New York College of Music, 1925-1926 (Box 51, Folder 13)
  - Catalogue of the New York College of Music, 1926-1927 (Box 51, Folder 14)
  - Catalogue of the New York College of Music, 1927-1928 (Box 51, Folder 15)
  - Catalogue of the New York College of Music, 1928-1929 (Box 51, Folder 16)
  - Catalogue of the New York College of Music, 1929-1930 (Box 51, Folder 17)
- Liberal Education Program (RG 21.29), 1981-1984
  - Bulletins, 1981-1984 (Box 52)
- Study Abroad Programs (RG 21.39), 1960-2005
  - NYU in Spain bulletins, 1960-1961, 1963-1971, 1973-1977, 1979-1981, 1987-1989 (Box 53)
  - Junior Year in Brazil bulletins, 1961-1964 (Box 53)
  - NYU in France bulletins, 1974-1977, 1985-1986, 1988-1989 (Box 53)
  - NYU in France bulletins, 1983-1985, 1996-1997 (Box 54)
  - NYU in London bulletins, 1978-1980, 1982, 1988-1989 (Box 54)
  - Bulletins, 1995, 1997, 1999-2005 (Box 54)
- NYU Washington, DC (RG 21.39.12), April 2017-ongoing
  - NYU Washington, DC Spring 2017 Courses, April 2017 (Box Electronic Records)
    Course descriptions for classes offered at the NYU Washington, DC campus. Also includes links to courses offered during Fall 2016, Fall 2017, and Spring 2018.
  - NYU Washington, DC Fall 2017 Courses, April-November 2017 (Box Electronic Records)
    Course descriptions for classes offered at the NYU Washington, DC campus. Also includes links to courses offered during Fall 2016, Spring 2017, and Spring 2018.
  - NYU Washington, DC Fall 2018 Courses, August 2018-March 2019 (Box Electronic Records)
    Course descriptions for classes offered at the NYU Washington, DC campus. Also includes links to courses offered during Spring 2019, Fall 2019, and Spring 2020.
  - NYU Washington, DC Spring 2019 Courses, October 2018-February 2019 (Box Electronic Records)
    Website for the NYU Washington, DC Spring 2019 course listings. Includes courses in business, economics, environmental studies, history, journalism, metropolitan studies, politics, public policy, and global leadership.
  - NYU Washington, DC Fall 2019 Courses, March-October 2019 (Box Electronic Records)
    This site lists courses that are offered by NYU in Washington, D.C. for Fall 2019 and includes number of credits for each course, brief course descriptions, and sample syllabi for each course.
  - NYU Washington, DC Spring 2020 Courses, March 2019-March 2020 (Box Electronic Records)
    This site lists courses that are offered by NYU in Washington, D.C. for Spring 2020 and includes number of credits for each course, brief course descriptions, and sample syllabi for each course.
  - NYU Washington, DC Courses, March 2019-June 2020 (Box Electronic Records)
    This page features course offerings, listed by semester, for NYU DC. There are pages for semesters through Spring of 2021. These pages feature course descriptions from business, economics, environmental studies, Gallatin, history, journalism, metropolitan studies, politics, and public policy departments. The page also links to information about the January and Summer Term programs.
  - NYU Washington, DC Fall 2020 Courses, October 2019-October 2020 (Box Electronic Records)
    This site lists courses that are offered by NYU in Washington, D.C. for Fall 2020 and includes number of credits for each course, brief course descriptions, and sample syllabi for each course.